This should look familiar to you.
この図を見てください
You should have seen it in course number two, launching into ML.
コース2の MLの開始で使用した図です
Remember we said ML models are mathematical functions with parameters and
MLモデルはパラメータと ハイパーパラメータを持つ数学関数です
A parameter is a real valued variable that changes during model training,
パタメータは変数で 値はモデルトレーニング中に変わります
like all those base and biases that we've come to know so well.
これまでに説明した ベースとバイアスと同様です
A hyper-parameter, on the other hand, is a setting that we set before training, and
ハイパーパラメータの値は トレーニング前に設定します
it doesn't change afterwards.
値は変わりません
Examples of hyper-parameters are learning rate, regularization rate, batch size,
ハイパーパラメータの例としては 学習率、正規化率、バッチサイズ
number of hidden layers in the neural net, and number of neurons in each layer.
ニューラルネットの隠れ層数、 各層のニューロン数などがあります
Now that you're clear about the differences between parameters and
2つの違いが明らかになったところで
hyper-parameters, let's shift our attention to hyper-parameters.
ハイパーパラメータを見ていきましょう
Since we know parameters are going to be adjusted by the training algorithm,
パラメータはトレーニングアルゴリズムで 調整するので
our job is to set the hyper-parameters, right?
ハイパーパラメータを設定します
In the previous module, we manually played with some of those hyper-parameters.
前のモジュールでは ハイパーパラメータを手動で設定し
For instance, we learned that batch size and and learning rate matter.
バッチサイズと学習率が 重要であることを学びました
Here I have some graphs from Andrej Karpathy's great article,
Andrej Karpathyの記事から グラフを引用します
that I recommend you review at your leisure.
ぜひ記事を参照してください
He visualizes the problem so well.
問題がよく可視化されています
As you see on the left, at the lower learning rate,
左側のグラフでは 学習率を低くすると
like the blue graph here, improvement is linear.
青曲線のように パフォーマンスが線形で向上します
But you often don't get the best possible performance.
ただし最大パフォーマンスは 通常得られません
At a high learning rate, like the green graph here, you get exponential
学習率を高くすると 緑曲線のように最初は大幅に向上しますが
improvement at first, but you often don't find the best possible performance.
最大パフォーマンスは 通常得られません
At the very high learning rate, like this yellow graph, you can get completely lost.
学習率を非常に高くすると 黄曲線のように完全に逸脱します
There's often a Goldilocks learning rate, like this red one here.
通常は赤曲線のように 適度な学習率がありますが
But good luck finding it.
見つけるのは困難です
Let's see what these graphs tell us about batch size.
グラフからバッチサイズの影響を確認します
On the right you see a very noisy loss curve, and
右側の損失曲線には かなりのノイズがあります
that's due to the small batch size.
バッチサイズが小さいためです
From previous module, you should remember that setting the batch size too large
バッチサイズが大きすぎると 処理速度が大幅に低下します
One thing to note though these graphs are by epoch but
これらのグラフはエポック基準ですが
unfortunately tensor flow doesn't know much about epochs.
TensorFlowには エポック情報が足りません
You'll have to figure out the epoch by calculating how many steps
エポックを明らかにするには 1エポックに相当する
of a given batch size will equate one epoch.
バッチサイズのステップ数を計算します
In other words you need to find out how many steps of given batch size you
つまり データセットを1回 走査するのに必要な
will be required to traverse your data set once.
バッチサイズのステップ数を計算します